Guide to the East Side House Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
East Side House Records,
1851-1992
East Side House Settlement.
18 linear ft. (in 43 boxes & 1 flat folder).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027
4079916
History
Social settlement founded in 1891 by Everett P. Wheeler and other members of the Church Club of the City of New York on Manhattan's East Side. Moved to the Bronx in 1963.
Scope and Content
The records include addresses, annual reports, correspondence, memos, minutes, program files, newsclippings, administrative records, photographs, video tape, and film. They include material dating from the decades prior to the establishment of the settlement which shed light on the philosophy and motivation of its founders, and offer a unique view of the first wave of the settlement house movement in America. The records document social conditions, demographic change, political activity and philanthropy in New York City. Addresses by East Side House founder Everett P. Wheeler, included in Series I, document his family history and career as a lawyer and civic reformer prior to the founding of East Side House. Wheeler's correspondence details his role in establishing the settlement and managing it during its first decades.
Administrative files in Series II on the East Side Club, the Webster Free Library and John Jay Park fill in the picture of East Side House during its early years. This series continues through the early 1990s and includes records of special events, fundraising, and other administrative matters.
Annual reports and minutes in Series III offer the most comprehensive view of the spectrum of settlement programs and services from its founding in 1891 to the 1990s.
The bulk of records in Series IV are from the period 1960-1990, and document East Side House's work in the South Bronx from the point of view of its executive staff. There are only a few items of correspondence from earlier periods in this series.
Program records in Series V also focus on the Bronx era, and include reports, participant statistics, and correspondence on such activities as youth recreation and employment counseling, senior citizen centers, and day care.
Photographs, films and video tape in Series VI document settlement program activities and participants, as well as board members and staff.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 7 series:
Series I: Everett P. Wheeler Papers
Series II: Administration
Series III: Board of Managers
Series IV: Resident Managers Headworkers and Executive Directors
Series V: Programs and Services
Series VI: Audio-Visual Materials
Series VII: Oversized Photographs
Subjects
Association of the Bar of the City of New York.; Church Club of the City of New York.; East Side House Settlement.; Episcopal Church.; New York Free Trade Club.; United Neighborhood Houses of New York, Inc. (New York, N.Y.).; Potter, Henry Codman, 1835-1908.; Wheeler, Everett Pepperell, 1840-1925.; Bronx (New York, N.Y.)--History.; Bronx (New York, N.Y.)--Social conditions.; New York (N.Y.)--History.; New York (N.Y.)--Social conditions.; Community centers--Bronx (New York, N.Y.).; Community centers--New York (N.Y.).; Human services--New York (N.Y.).; Immigrants--New York (N.Y.).; Public housing--New York (N.Y.).; Social service--Bronx (New York, N.Y.).; Social service--New York (N.Y.).; Social settlements--New York (N.Y.).; Social work--Bronx (New York, N.Y.).; Social work--New York (N.Y.).; Welfare--New York (N.Y.).; Administrative records; Announcements.; Annual reports.; Articles of incorporation.; Audio tapes.; Autobiographies.; Brochures.; Budgets.; Bylaws.; Calendars.; Certificates.; Financial records.; Fliers (printed matter).; Legal documents.; Lists.; Manuals.; Memorandums.; Minutes.; Motion pictures (visual works).; Negatives.; Organizational charts.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Reports.; Rosters.; Schedules.; Speeches.; Tape cassettes.; Transparencies.; Video tapes.; Child welfare workers.; Social workers.; Women social workers.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
09/23/1994 M-94-09-23 Records East Side House Gift
Gift of East Side House, 1994.
- Series I: Everett P. Wheeler Papers
  - Subseries I.1: Addresses (Bound Volume)
    - David Everett Wheeler "A Discourse Delivered at the Request of the Order of United Americans", 1851 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - David Everett Wheeler "A Paper Read Before the American Geographical and Statistical Society", 1856 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Character and Conduct of the War", 1862 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Supreme Court as a Co-ordinate Branch of the United States Government", 1860 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Petition of Bar Association for Additional Judges in Second Circuit", 1877 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Report on Bill Increasing Number Circuit Judges and Establishing General Terms in Each Circuit", 1882 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Clarkson N. Potter", 1882 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Reports on Committee of International Law", 1896-1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Law of Prize", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Debate on Civil Service Reform Before the Seventh Congress of the Protestant Episcopal Church", 1881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Report of New York City Civil Service Commission", 1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Papers on Tariff Reform", 1882-1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Acceptance of Nomination for Governor", 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Louisbourg Expedition of 1745", 1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Oration and Poem Delivered Before the Associated Alumni of the College of the City of New York", 1866 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Lectureship on Architecture and the Art of Design", 1878 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Report in Relation to the Admission of Students to the College of the City of New York", 1878 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Progressive Element in American Life", 1882 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Duty of the United States to the American Citizens in Turkey", 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Rights of American Citizens in Turkey", 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Influence of the United States Upon Great Britain During the 19th Century", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Reports of the Special Committee of Church Club", 1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Everett P. Wheeler East Side House Annual Reports, 1891-98 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Subseries I.2: Addresses
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Sir William Pepperrell", 1887 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Louisbourg Expedition of 1745", 1895 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Influence of the United States Upon Great Britain During the 19th Century", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Harter Act", 1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Law of Prize", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Proceedings at the Annual Dinner of the New York Free Trade Club", 1884 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "Wages and the Tariff", 1888 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Progressive Element in American Life", 1882 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler East Side House Annual Reports, 1891-1894 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Duty of the United States to the American Citizens in Turkey", 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Everett P. Wheeler "The Rights of American Citizens in Turkey", 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1890-91 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1893-95 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1906-07 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Sixty Years of American Life, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      [Bound volume]
- Series II: Administration
  - Administrative Plans, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Alumni, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Anniversaries, 1941-87 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Anniversary, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annual Dinner, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Articles of Incorporation-Amendments, 1916-1937 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1937-1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Asbestos Report, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bronx Cluster of Settlement Houses, 1983-91 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bronx Council on the Arts, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Building Construction, 1901-1904 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - By-Laws, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - By-Laws, 1900-06 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - By-Laws, 1914-45 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - By-Laws, 1961-88 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Carreker Correspondence, 1976-83 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Centennial, 1990-91 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Certificate of Change of Location, 1962-63 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Church Club, 1890-1907 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - City of New York. Bureau of Labor Services, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - City of New York. Bureau of Labor Services, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - City of New York. Bureau of Labor Services, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - City of New York. Miscellaneous, 1981-91 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - City of New York. Senior Citizen Advisory Committee, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Community Board #1, 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Community Statistics, 1960-61 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cultural Committee, 1988-89 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Development--J.C. GeeverInc., 1978-84 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Development--J.C. GeeverInc., 1985-87 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Development--J.C. GeeverInc., 1988-91 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - East Side Club, 1891-95 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - East Side Colleagues, 1895 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, 1981-91 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Food for Survival, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Funding Appeals, 1895-1908 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Greater New York Fund/United Way, 1981-86 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Haven Relief Fund, 1985-90 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Histories, 1953-85 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Japanese Chamber of Commerce, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Job Announcements and Descriptions, 1970's-80's (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - John Jay Park, 1894-1914 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Law Suits-Day, 1981-82 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Law Suits-Juran, 1981-85 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Law Suits-Clark, 1985-88 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Law Suits-McGee, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Law Suits-Richardson, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Law Suits-Pitts, 1984-86 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Mount Olivet Baptist Church, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Museum of the City of New York, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Neighborhood Guild, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - New York University Nursing Program, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Organization Charts, 1980's (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Personnel Policies, 1964-91 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Philip Morris, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Press Clippings, 1950's-80's (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases, 1981-91 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Press Release-Mission Statement, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Public Housing, 1981-82 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Publications--"A Neighborhood Place", 1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Publications--Brochures, 1957-90 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Publications--"East Side House Bulletin", 1905 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Publications--Newsletter, 1990-91 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Publications--"The South Southeast Bronx", 1965 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Publications--Saint Benedict the Moor, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Staff, 1970's-90's (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Staff Meetings, 1940-91 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - New York State, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Tax Assessments, 1891-1911 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Correspondence, 1981-92 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Executive Directors Council, 1989-92 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Ford Advisory Committee, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Report-"Grow Your Own: Personnel Recruitment and Retention in New York City's Settlement Houses", 1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Report-"Increasing the Effectiveness and Replicability of the Settlement House", 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Report-"United Neighborhood Houses: Past and Prospects", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Staff Development, 1990-91 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Strategic Planning Committee, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - United Neighborhood Houses "Small Victories", 1991 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - United Neighborhood Houses Survey, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - United States Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - United States Treasury Department, 1937-59 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - United Way, 1986-91 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - United Way Fundraisers, 1989-91 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - University Settlement Society, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Water Bills, 1892-1903 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Webster Free Library, 1893-1944 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Series III: Board of Managers
  - Annual Meetings, 1907-19 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meetings, 1920-29 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meetings, 1930-36 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meetings, 1940-45 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meetings, 1946-59 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Annual Meetings, 1960-69 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Annual Meetings, 1970-79 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meetings, 1980-89 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Annual Meetings, 1990-91 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1890-1900 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    [Bound Volume]
  - Annual Reports, 1890-1908 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    [ Bound Volume]
  - Annual Reports, 1901-08 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    [(Bound Volume)]
  - Annual Reports, 1909-19 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1891-94 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1895-98 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1900-01 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 19021904 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1905-06 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1907-08 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Annual Reports, 1909-10 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports, 1911-12 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Annual Reports, 1913-14 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1915-16 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1917-18 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1920-21 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1922-23 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1923-24 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1925-26 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Annual Reports, 19271929 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1942-43 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Annual Reports, 1946-47 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Annual Reports, 1948-49 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1950-51 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1952-53 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1954-55 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1956-57 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 19621964-65 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Annual Reports, 1966-67 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Attendance Lists, 1983-84 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Committees--Building, [nd] (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Committees--Executive-Minutes, 1911, 1922-29 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Committees--Executive-Minutes, 1939-59 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Committees--Finance-Auditor's Reports, 1986-90 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Committees--Finance-Budgets, 1935-91 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Committees--Finance-Correspondence, 1983-89 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Committees--Finance-Endowment Fund, 1986-90 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Committees--Finance-Fiduciary Trust Company, 1986-88 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Committees--Finance-J.C. GeeverInc.Reports, 1986-91 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Committees--Finance-Minutes, 18951905 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Committees--Finance-Minutes, 1907-19 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Committees--Finance-Minutes, 1920-28 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Committees--Finance-Minutes, 1930-89 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1892-1909 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1936-39 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1943-45 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1946-50 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1951-54 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1955-57 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1959-60 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1961-62 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1963-65 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1966-67 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1979-83 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1981-84 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1986-88 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Committees--Finance-Reports, 1989-91 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Committees--Membership, 1983-84 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Committees--Miscellaneous, 1902-90 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Committees--Music School, 1920-24 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Committees--On Reorganization, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Committees--On Work Among Men and Boys, 1921-23 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Committees--Planning for the ESH Exploratory Study, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Committees--Women's Auxiliary, 1918-20 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1982-90 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Manhattan Property, 1939-62 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Manual, 1967 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Manual, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1891 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1892-97 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1897-1910 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1899-1909 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1911-19 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1920-29 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1930-39 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1940-41 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1942-49 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1950-54 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1955-59 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1960-63 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1964-65 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1973-74 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1975-76 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1977-78 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1979-80 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - President/Executive Director List, 1891-1962 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Rosters, 1960-91 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Schedules of Meetings, 1982-91 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Winter Antique Show, 1954-79 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Winter Antique Show, 1980-88 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Winter Antique Show, 1989-90 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Winter Antique Show, 1990-91 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Resident Managers Headworkers and Executive Directors
  - Clarence Gordon, 1902 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - M. de G. Trenholm, [nd] (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Helen Hart, 1922-24 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Grace Gosselin, 1946-49 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Grace Gosselin-Lindquist Correspondence, 1961-67 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Grace Gosselin-Lindquist Research and Action Project, 1962-64 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - William Schnappauf Correspondence, 1981-89 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - William Schnappauf Retirement, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - John Sanchez Correspondence, 1989-90 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - John Sanchez Correspondence, 1991-92 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - John Sanchez Daring Goals For a Caring New York, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Series V: Programs and Services
  - Black History Month, 1990-91 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Bronx Week, 1981-82 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - City of New York. Human Resources Administration Correspondence, 1980-91 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Annual Program Reports, 1986-91 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Contract-Youth Program, 1986-87 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Contract-Youth Program, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Contract-Youth Program, 1989-90 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Correspondence, 1982-90 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Monthly Program Reports, 1980-83 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Program Statistics, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Program Statistics, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Program Statistics, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposal-After School, 1982-83 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposal-After School, 1987-88 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposal-Community Board Fair Share, 1989-91 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposals-Mill Brook, 1981-82 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposals-Mill Brook, 1982-83 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposals-Patterson, 1981-82 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposals-Patterson, 1982-83 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposals-Patterson, 1983-84 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposals-Youth Program, 1988-89 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposals-Youth Program, 1990-91 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Quarterly Reports, 1985-88 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Monthly Reports, 1989-91 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - City of New York. Youth Bureau Proposals, 1990-91 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Clubs and Classes, 1907 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Community Task Force on Immunization, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Comprehensive Employment Training Act VI, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Award, 1989-91 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Day Camp, 1979-91 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Day Camp-Registration Lists, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Demonstration Youth Employment Project, 1978-80 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Educational Program, 1989-90 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Ethiopia Fundraiser, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Family Day Care, 1979-92 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Fellow Citizenship Association, 1897 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Fresh Air Fund, 1980-91 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Head Start, 1979-91 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - I.S. 183, 1981-83 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Kindergarten, 1893 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Melrose-Mott Haven Community Center, 1980-91 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Melrose-Mott Haven Senior Center, 1982-90 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Mill Brook Community Center, 1981-89 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Mini-School, 1981-89 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Mitchel Community Center, 1981-89 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Mitchel Senior Center, 1980-83 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Mott Haven Community Center, 1980-1989 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Narcotics Education, 1989-90 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Neighborhood Prevention Network, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 12)